## **KAT TOW**

(+1) 608 931 4465 kattow88@gmail.com kattow.com

## **ABOUT ME**

I'm a left-brain/right-brain hybrid type. I'm an LX and UX designer with front-end development skills and an endless appetite for new knowledge. I have 4 years of professional design experience. I'm passionate about the power of data and design to improve everyday experiences.

## **SKILLS**

#### **DESIGN SKILLS**

- User research & testing
- Wireframing/prototyping
- Solution design: personas, sketching, user stories
- Information architecture
- Interaction design
- UI, web, & print design
- Learning experience design

#### **DEVELOPMENT SKILLS**

- HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap, CSS Grid, Flexbox
- JavaScript, jQuery

#### SOFTWARE/TOOLSETS

- Sketch, Figma
- Adobe: Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, XD
- Google Analytics
- Adapt, Lectora
- Microsoft: Word, Excel, Powerpoint, Outlook

#### OTHER SKILLS

- Product strategy
- Communication design
- Survey & interview development
- Storytelling

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Sept 2017 - present

Online Learning Developer INTERNATIONAL **FOUNDATION OF EMPLOYEE BENEFIT PLANS** 

Mar - July 2017

Digital Designer 2-STORY CREATIVE

## July 2014 - Mar 2017

Director of Marketing & Design RENAISSANCE **THEATERWORKS** 

#### **RESPONSIBILITIES**

- Design and develop user-centered interactive learning experiences that support modern technology and models of instructional design
- Manage various project content collaborators and communicate project goals, expectations, and progress
- Provide recommendations for instructional design, sequencing, assessment and evaluation

#### **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- Proposed, and led the transition from paginated, unresponsive courses (Lectora) to fully responsive & interactive courses (Adapt) improving usability, understandability, and accessibility
- Designed & developed custom CSS for online courses
- Developed new design standards for online courses

#### **RESPONSIBILITIES**

- Created designs from concept to final proof for print, web, & social.
- Built data-driven user personas & wrote user stories
- Front-end design & development in WordPress

#### **RESPONSIBILITIES**

- Managed company website
- Managed communications, audience development, & marketing
- Coordinated content, design, & executuion of company communications across team & vendors
- Trained team on website & social media management
- Designed season graphic & marketing materials

#### **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- Increased single ticket sales by 40% over two years
- Redesigned & built company website to be fully responsive, improving user experience and accessibility while improving the ecommerce process.

## **EDUCATION**

Sep 2017 - present **UW Milwaukee** 

Jan 2017 - present

freeCodeCamp edX

**IDF** 

Coursera

# Sep 2007 - Jun 2011

Lawrence University

#### MS | INFORMATION SCIENCE & TECHNOLOGY

**Human Computer Interaction** 

### SELECTED SELF-STUDY COURSES (incomplete list)

- Principles of Designing for Humans
- Evaluating Designs with Users
- UX Design: From Concept to Wireframe
- User Experience: Research & Prototyping

### DESIGN FOR THEATER | GENDER STUDIES

Capstones in scenic design & art history